JAY QUIGLEY

V

 \bowtie

in

0

850.274.1846

SF Bay Area

quigley.james.g @gmail.com in/jamesgquigley

iavqui

SUMMARY

Tenacious, driven, detail-oriented communicator and activist with a doctorate in questioning assumptions. Resourceful, rapid learner with extensive experience teaching, writing, and volunteering. Affable teammate dedicated to establishing communication and rapport among colleagues. Working proficiency in Spanish.

EMPLOYMENT EXPERIENCE

COVERHOUND & CYBERPOLICY

San Francisco, California

Software Engineer

Ост. 2016 - Ост. 2018

- Mentored numerous other developers on tools with which they were unfamiliar
- Crafted Ruby/Rails and React JS code to send data between applications via REST API, to handle attachment uploads to AWS, to enhance search capabilities with Elasticsearch, and more
- Integrated the codebase with numerous outside platforms, including Google OAuth ("log in with Google"), automating Slack messages, and streamlining email marketing with ActiveCampaign

AVANT

Chicago, Illinois

Junior Software Engineer

FEB. - JUL. 2016

- Self-taught ReactJS & EcmaScript 2015 to build a Monthly Net Income Calculator, saving Avant an estimated \$60,000 annually in call center specialist productivity
- Consistently practiced test-driven development (esp. in Rspec, Mocha), and improved problem-solving strategies (e.g. searching through app of over 60,000 files)

FLORIDA STATE UNIVERSITY

Tallahassee, Florida

Graduate Instructor, Teaching Assistant, Ph.D. Student

2007-2015

- Honed superb critical thinking and writing skills via 17 graduate seminars on topics as diverse as ethics, epistemology, and formal logic, plus 1 peer-reviewed publication and a doctoral dissertation
- Gained experience explaining difficult concepts simply, giving constructive feedback, and inspiring students to think critically. Coached the FSU Undergraduate Ethics Bowl team for three seasons.
- Sharpened public speaking skills by teaching 3 university courses, TAing for an additional 15, and presenting at 4 professional conferences and 7 student philosophy conferences

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

OAKLAND CITY COUNCIL

Oakland, California

Policy Intern

Nov - DEC. 2018

- Drafted two bills and one resolution
- Assisted with research helpful for passing a seismic retrofit ordinance

BERKELEY COALITION FOR ANIMALS

Berkeley, California

Co-founder

2016-present

- Successfully campaigned to make Berkeley the 2nd US city to ban the sale of fur apparel
- Helped the city of Berkeley decide to go meat-free on Mondays for all city institutions.

ANIMAL CHARITY EVALUATORS

Remote

Intern

May - Aug. 2014

- Drafted the organization's first development and fundraising plan, in part by networking with numerous nonprofit directors about their fundraising experiences and reading suggestions
- Assembled 17 letters of intent for grant applications and one full grant application
- Piloted a study on the effectiveness of video outreach promoting vegan food choices

EDUCATION

FLORIDA STATE UNIVERSITY, Tallahassee, Fla., **Ph.D.**, **Philosophy**, 2015 FLORIDA STATE UNIVERSITY, Tallahassee, Fla., **M.A.**, **Philosophy**, 2009 TRUMAN STATE UNIVERSITY, Kirksville, Mo., **BA**, **Philosophy and Religion**, Spanish minor, 2007